STEPHEN MOURITSEN CHIANG

www.linkedin.com/in/chiangs

+45 28 26 99 70 | stephen.e.chiang@gmail.com **(**

[28.12.1981]



2016-CURRENT

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Consult and develop full-stack and front-end solutions for non-profits and small businesses. Improve flow and presentation of information to drive conversion rates

2016-CURRENT

OPERATIONS MANAGER - Iskilde ApS

Manage operations and production, cost control, customer support, IT support, and regulatory compliance

2015-2016

MARKET DEVELOPMENT MANAGER - Schindler Elevator Generate business, build strategic relationships

2005-2015

LEADER IN MULTIPLE POSITIONS- US Dept of Defense

Consult foreign civilian and military project groups Analyse information and provide operational planning data Lead, manage, and train teams of up to 40 personnel Build new organizational capabilities

Projects, Travels & Interests

Sri Lanka & Maldives - 2013

Laos - 2012

South Korea - 2011

www.github.com/chiangs codehammer.design parkr.city

systematicresumes.com antonia-designs.com

www.chiangs.ninja @ : The fun is finding new ways to apply the knowledge I've acquired from unrelated paths and fields to find creative and efficient solutions.

EDUCATION

2017 Skill Distillery, Full Stack Java Development

2016 - 2017 Free Code Camp, Full Stack Programming

2007 - 2012 Trident University International, M.B.A. International Business

2000 - 2005 Seattle University, Bachelor of Criminal Justice

Languages

English

Danish

Mandarin Chinese

Bahasa Indonesia

Spanish

💁 Java

</> HTML </> JavaScript

{} CSS / SASS

Programs, Frameworks, & Tools

Git / GitHub

Atom / Spring Tool Suite

Bower, Grunt

JUnit

Amazon Web Svc

MySQL

AngularJS

RESTful services

ABOUT

The common thread in my career has been delving into new and unfamiliar fields and learning quickly to bring value to the team and customer. My travels all over the world has introduced me to many walks of life, and that has helped me to learn how to adapt to best facilitate communication and teamwork.

As a coder, I believe I'm not living unless I'm learning new things and applying them to my work. I continue to master the technologies I'm familiar with, but always on the lookout for new ways of doing things to expand my ability to solve problems.

I look for volunteer opportunities to assist non-profits with their web development needs and currently looking to contribute to open-source projects.



Consistent, top-rated leader with 15 years of experience in complex, long-term project striving to become a world-class software developer.

About Stephen

I'm a junior developer who has proven to be a fast learner and hard worker. I believe solutions and new knowledge are only of value if they are implemented well and deliberately. I love solving problems with logic and using my eye for design to present them in an appealing way to the customer. I read blogs and listen to podcasts daily, I also write my own (https://www.chiangs.ninja/blog) and take on volunteer or low-profit work through my own business entity (https://www.codehammer.design) to continue to code and stretch my knowledge. I believe in being a part of a team and ensuring their success as a key to my own.

Most of my coding experience is building full-stack web apps for startups and for personal growth. Examples of them can be found on my GitHub Profile (https://www.github.com/chiangs), my personal portfolio site (https://www.chiangs/ninja/projects), and various customers (https://www.parkr.city and https://www.systematicresumes.com).

I love learning new technologies and frameworks, studying design and UI/UX and playing with ways to effectively integrate all of it. I am launching my new career as a developer after spending 12 years with the US Army as a Special Operations Officer, working as a foreign military consultant and project manager and earning a Masters of Business Administration, and a certificate in full-stack Java web development.

Languages	Technologies	Tools
Java 8	Spring Framework	Atom IDE
Linux	Angular Framework (v1.5 and up)	Eclipse / Sprint STS IDE
MySQL	Bootstrap	Git / GitHub
HTML5 / CSS / JavaScript	Bower / Grunt / Yeoman	Adobe Lightroom
PHP (learning)	Amazon Web Services	
MongoDB (learning)	RESTful Web Services	
	JUnit	
Practices - Skills	Ionic Framework (learning)	
Object Oriented Programming	JQuery	
Test-Driven Development	WordPress	
MVC , MV* Patterns	Google Analytics	
Agile / Scrum (pursuing certification)	API development and integration	

Experience

Full-Stack Web Development

Self-taught and became certified as a full-stack developer and continue on a deliberate track of education on latest technologies. Started my own company (Code & Hammer) to provide full-stack web development for local artists, musicians, startups, non-profits and small businesses as a way to continue to learn and give back to my community.

- Consulted and provided web application development services consisting of full-stack programming and developing RESTful architecture and UI/UX optimisation for 2 startups. Assisted another startup in setting up online business and customer engagement.
- Provided volunteer front-end refresh for a US-based non-profit to assist them in improving communication of information and optimising conversion of visitor to donor.
- Currently studying to certify as an Agile / Scrum Developer.

Project Management and Change Management

Led teams for an organization of over 1,200 personnel to create solutions in austere, complex, and remote conditions. Formalized operations for a growing company to enhance control over processes and costs. Experienced in building and facilitating temporary-permanent networks at the executive/diplomatic level.

- Led project team in a foreign market to conceptualize and implement a program of 40 projects that eliminated over \$600,000 of projected capital expenditure while still achieving optimal effects of strategic goals.
- Negotiated and implemented two portfolios of capacity building programs worth over \$4 million through three fiscal years as part of a strategic collaborative effort with foreign civilian, military and government stakeholders.
- Developed and implemented systems of organizational knowledge continuity and best practices that drove continuous improvement processes for all operational functions for an organization of 1,200 personnel.
- Developed and implemented a new strategic capability for an organization dedicated to responding to global crises.
- Optimized and formalized operational processes to reduce variation in expected outcomes of the supply chain.
- Turned a fixed operational cost of 22.500 DKK into an income of 500 DKK through creative partnerships and green initiatives.

Leader and Mentor

Managed the training, development, and mentorship of junior staff and positioned them in opportunities to grow into leadership positions of higher responsibility and impact. Evaluated performance and goals to ensure optimal career satisfaction in junior staff.

- Managed a team of eight that streamlined training in language, culture, negotiations and interpersonal skills, critical analysis, and executive communications for a globally dispersed organization of 30 personnel.
- Developed and mentored 11 junior staff members in professional development, academic curiosity, and personal goal achievements with 99% promotion and retention rate.
- Successfully filled three senior positions for a total of 12 months in strategic planning teams.

Employment History

Sep 2016 to Present:	Freelance Web Development, Code & Hammer	Denmark
Oct 2015 to Present:	Operations Manager, Iskilde ApS	Denmark
Oct 2014 to Oct 2015:	Market Development Manager, Schindler Elevator Corporation	USA
Jan 2014 – Oct 2014:	Deputy Director, Strategic Planning Team, US Army	USA
Nov 2012 - Dec 2013:	Team Lead, South Asia, US Army	Sri Lanka / Maldives
May 2011- Oct 2012:	Team Lead, Asia Pacific, US Army	Laos / USA
Sep 2010 - Apr 2011:	Deputy Director, Operational Planning Team, US Army	S. Korea / USA
Jun 2008 – Aug 2010:	Student in Military Professional Development Courses	USA
Jan 2007 – May 2008:	Director of Operations, US Army	Iraq / USA
Apr 2006 – Dec 2007:	Project Lead, Support and Logistics Operations, US Army	Iraq / USA
Aug 2005 – May 2006:	Director, Maintenance and Logistics, US Army	Iraq / USA

Education and Interests

2012 M.B.A. International Business2005 B.C.J. Forensic Psychology

Trident University International, Cypress, CA.
Seattle University, Seattle, WA.

Certifications

- Full-stack Java Web Development, 2017, Skill Distillery
- Full-Stack Web Development, 2017, Free Code Camp
- Project Management Professional (PMP), 2014, Project Management Institute
- Lean Six Sigma (LSS) training, 2014, Solomon-Eos
- All-Source Analyst, 2012, Defense Intelligence Agency
- Advanced Negotiations and Mediation, 2012, Phoenix Group

Languages

- English Native
- Mandarin Chinese Working verbal
- Danish Working
- Indonesian Basic

Interests

- Innovations in technology, science, design and business
- Amateure Photography
- Team Sports
- Muay Thai Boxing